Peter Harmazinski

Houston, TX

pharmazinski@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/peterharmazinski/

Summary

Professional developer who specializes in analytics and data visualization. Passionate about user experience, mentoring, improving processes, and continuous learning. Recognized as a Lean Champion, Code for Good technical judge, and a Champion of Chase.

Technology

• Tableau • SQL • Alteryx • Python • React • JavaScript

Experience

Tableau Lead Developer, Cigna/Evernorth

11/2020 - Current

- Partner with stakeholders, business analysts, and other developers to discover requirements, gather
 and transform data, design wireframes, and implement performant and responsive Tableau
 dashboards for audiences at all levels, resulting in reusable dashboards adopted across multiple
 lines of business.
- Design and implement data migration strategy to support firmwide initiative towards common curated data sources, resulting in spurring on other teams to take similar initiatives.
- Create and maintain a Tableau community chat to foster cross-team collaboration and knowledge share.
- Provide mentorship to internal and external team members on analytics, design, technology, programming, and career development.

Business Intelligence Developer, JPMorgan Chase

03/2018 - 11/2020

- Created Tableau and React dashboards to visualize metrics, simultaneously automating the process
 of collecting the data and improving the understandability of the information, resulting in 30,000+
 dashboard views per year.
- Implemented Alteryx and Node.js workflows and deploy to server to automate extraction, transformation, and loading of data from databases to Tableau Server and SharePoint.
- Formulated metrics to analyze testing data, which is reported monthly to managers and executives, thereby empowering management with more accurate information to make actionable decisions.

Web Developer, JPMorgan Chase

03/2017 - 03/2018

- Migrated the JPMorgan Markets container and admin applications from Oracle to Cassandra, thereby improving query speed by 75%.
- Created Splunk dashboards to visualize high- and low-level performance differences between Oracle and Cassandra, thereby ensuring a lens through which to identify issues and make improvements.

Business Systems Analyst, JPMorgan Chase

08/2015 - 03/2017

- Designed and developed JavaScript dashboards to replace manual reporting, resulting in 270+ hours saved per year.
- Managed software release pilots by reviewing, triaging, and resolving issues with IT partners, conducting global conference calls with business managers, and multichannel communication.

Fraud Analyst, JPMorgan Chase

03/2014 - 08/2015

• Led implementation of new reports by creating presentations, developing and conducting training, and analyzing data to look for trends, thereby receiving the award for Champion of Chase.

Online Technical Support Specialist, JPMorgan Chase

03/2013 - 03/2014

• Solved customers' problems efficiently by multitasking, thinking outside of the box, and asking appropriate questions to determine core issues, which resulted in a 99% customer satisfaction rate.

Russian Linguist Team Leader, United States Army

08/2003 - 08/2008

• Researched, gathered, organized, and reported data in a time-sensitive environment. As a result of working individually and as a member of a team, 100% of the strategic goals were achieved.

Education

- Master's degree in Data Analytics (2020): Western Governors University
- Associate's degree in Computer Information Systems (2016): Florida Institute of Technology
- Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration (2011): University of the Incarnate Word

Certifications

- SAS Statistical Business Analyst
- SAS Base Programming Specialist
- Alteryx Designer Core

Affiliations

- Data Visualization Society
- Data Science Association
- Association for Computing Machinery

Service

- Viz for Social Good
- Code for Good
- Resolutions Hospice